Finding Aid for the Geoff Miller Los Angeles Magazine records, 1950-2011
UCLA Library Special Collections
Geoff Miller Los Magazine records
1950-2011
2212
UCLA Library Special Collections
6.4 linear ft. (11 boxes, 17 magazine boxes, 6 flat boxes.)
Geoff Miller was co-founder and served as editor and publisher of Los Angeles Magazine. The collection consists of a small number of published writings by Miller, a small number of photographs, a small amount of material documenting Los Angeles Magazine’s operations, and issues of Los Angeles Magazine.
Miller, Geoff
Restrictions on Access
COLLECTION STORED OFF-SITE AT SRLF: Open for research. Advance notice required for access. Contact the UCLA Library Special Collections Reference Desk for paging information.
Biography/History
George Geoffrey Miller was born in Salt Lake City on August 1, 1936. He earned his B.A. (1958) and M.A.in Journalism (1959) from the University of California, Los Angeles. While doing his graduate work at UCLA, Miller began developing a format for a city magazine. In 1960, he teamed with David Brown, an ad executive, to launch Los Angeles, known at the time as The Southern California Prompter. Miller served as editor in chief from 1974 until 1990, when he was appointed publisher. During his time as editor, Los Angeles Magazine was one of the most successful magazines of its type in the United States. Miller was awarded the first Irwin R. Blacker Award from the University of Southern California for Distinguished Contribution to Literature in Southern California. He retired from the magazine in 1994 and continued to work in the publishing field as a consultant. In 2006 Miller was diagnosed with Progressive Supra-nuclear Palsey and died April 16, 2011 in Los Angeles, California.
Scope and Content
The collection consists of material related to the career of Los Angeles Magazine editor and publisher Geoff Miller. Included are a small number of published writings by Miller, a small number of photographs, a small amount of material documenting Los Angeles Magazine’s operations, and a small number of other Los Angeles related magazines. The bulk of the collection consists of Los Angeles Magazine publications.
Series 1. Geoff Miller papers (1954 - 2011; Box 1,3) The Geoff Miller papers series consists of a small amount of articles, letters, speeches, and assorted publications which document Miller’s educational background and career as an editor and publisher for Los Angeles Magazine.
Series 2. Los Angeles Magazine documents and publications (1959 - 2006; Box 1-28) The bulk of the series consists of issues of Los Angeles Magazine (1960- 2007). Also included are a small amount of early promotional materials, a small amount of advertising information, editorial and story ideas, and clippings regarding the magazine’s ownership and influence on Los Angeles.
Series 3. Magazine publications (1950s-1990s; Box 1, 29-35) The series consists of a assorted magazine publications collected by Miller. The publications contain stories or information related to Los Angeles and/or Southern California which Miller considered significant or newsworthy. Some of the pieces may have inspired story ideas for Los Angeles Magazine.
Organization and Arrangement
The collection is arranged in the following series:
Series 1. Geoff Miller papers
Series 2. Los Angeles Magazine documents and publications
Series 3. Magazine publications.
UCLA Catalog Record ID
UCLA Catalog Record ID: 7421029
Container List
- Geoff Miller papers., Bulk, 1954-1992.; 1954-1992; 2011.
  - Geoff Miller speeches and notes., ca. 1974-1985. (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Assorted publications from UCLA and Loyola University., 1954-1961. (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Best Articles and Stories (1 issue) and UCLA Review Magazine (2 issues) with articles by Geoff Miller.., 1958-1960. (Box 1, Folder 7)
    Scope and Content
  - In Memoriam from the County of Los Angeles Board of Supervisors., 2011 Apr 19. (Box 3, Folder 12)
    General note
    Signed by Zev Yaroslavsky.
  - Los Angeles Board of Supervisors recognition to Los Angeles Magazine for Riot Relief Contributions., 1992 Nov 11. (Box 3, Folder 13)
    Press release and 2 photographs.
  - Photographs., ca. 1970s-ca. 1990s. (Box 3, Folder 10)
    Images of Geoff Miller and others such as: Dyan Cannon, Groucho Marx, Joyce Haber, and Kathryn Leigh Scott among others.
  - Wedding announcement for Geoff Miller and Kathryn Leigh Scott.., 1991. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Westwind (with article by Miller)., Fall, 1958. (Box 1, Folder 5)
    Article title: If One Should Fall.
  - UCLA memorabilia., no date, ca. 1960. (Box 1, Folder 2)
    Prompter article by Miller and journalism graduate class poster.
- Los Angeles Magazine documents and publications., 1959-2006.
  - Advertising and circulation reports., 1980s. (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Advertising Lineage., 1990s. (Box 3, Folder 7)
    boxscore, circulation, linage reports clipping, some related to Buzz magazine.
  - Assorted clippings and tears outs., early 1970s to early 2000s. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Business documents., 1970s. (Box 3, Folder 5)
    Advertising, circulation, financial, and employment contracts.
  - Julie Cameron's piece about Washington and Los Angeles., 1979. (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Clippings about Los Angeles Magazine., 1994-2003. (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Early promotional materials for Los Angeles Magazine., 1960s-1970s. (Box 2, Folder 1)
    With newspaper and radio copy; some with hand written notes that may be by Dave Brown and Miller.
  - Editorial stories and ideas., 1973-1978. (Box 1, Folder 12)
    Appears to be for Los Angeles Magazine.
  - Editorial focus., 1979. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Clipping and tear outs about Europe., late 1960s to late 1970s. (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Me and Her South of the Boarder by Lorin Maazel (written for Los Angeles Magazine)., 1975. (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Layout ideas., ca. 1979-1980. (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Layout for Financial Planning Who'll Earn What in '76., 1976. (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Letters., mid 1970s to early 2000s. (Box 1, Folder 10)
    Mostly referencing Los Angeles Magazine.
  - News stand sales., ca. 1963. (Box 3, Folder 4)
    w/ layout notes not dated
  - New West (California) vs. Los Angeles Magazine (folder 1 of 2)., ca. 1980. (Box 3, Folder 8)
    Magazine wars w/ New West strategy, memos, and clippings.
  - New West (California) vs. Los Angeles Magazine (folder 2 of 2)., 1976-1981. (Box 3, Folder 9)
    Magazine wars w/ New West. New West journal (4 issues) and WJR (1 issue)
  - Story idea topics., 1960s-1970s. (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Berry Gordy: The Story that Killed Joyce Haber., ca. 1959. (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Subscription mailer samples., ca. 1961. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issue The New South Bay)., 1965 May. (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (possible 15 year anniversary)., 1975. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - LosAngeles Magazine 25th Anniversary., 1985. (Box 2, Folder 5)
    memos, corr., and ideas
  - LosAngeles Magazine 30th Anniversary issue and press kit., 1990 July. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1960 and 1962. (Box 4)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1963 and 1964. (Box 5)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1965 and 1966. (Box 6)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1967 and 1968. (Box 7)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1969 and 1970. (Box 8)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1971 and 1972. (Box 9)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1973. (Box 10)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1975. (Box 11)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (bound volumes)., 1975. (Box 12)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1976-1977. (Box 13)
    Volume 21, number 6-8, 10-12; Volume 22, number 2, 4, 8-11.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1977-1978. (Box 14)
    Volume 22, numbers 11, 12; Volume 23, numbers 5, 8-12.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1979. (Box 15)
    Volume 24, numbers 1, 4-8, 10, 11.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1979-1980. (Box 16)
    Volume 24, number 12; Volume 25, numbers 1-8.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1980-1981. (Box 17)
    Volume 25: numbers 9-12; Volume 26, numbers 1,4,5,8,9.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1981-1982. (Box 18)
    Volume 26,numbers 10-12; Volume 27, numbers 2-4, 11, 12.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1983-1984. (Box 19)
    Volume 28, numbers 2-5, 11, Volume 29, numbers 1, 2, 4-5.
  - Los Angeles Magazine's Olympic Guide., 1984. (Box 10)
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1984-1985. (Box 20)
    Volume 29,numbers 6, 8-12; Volume 30, numbers 2, 5.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1985-1987. (Box 21)
    Volume 30, numbers 8, 10, 12; Volume 31, numbers 2, 3, 5; Volume 32, numbers 2-6.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1987-1988. (Box 22)
    Volume 32, numbers 7-12; Volume 33, numbers 1-4.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1988-1989. (Box 23)
    Volume 33, numbers 5-12; Volume 34, numbers 5, 7.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1989-1992. (Box 24)
    Volume 34, number 12; Volume 35, numbers 1, 2, 4, 7, 8; Volume 36, numbers 8, 12; Volume 37, numbers 1, 2, 4-7.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1992-1995. (Box 25)
    Volume 37, numbers 2, 4, 6; Volume 39, numbers 4-8; Volume 39, number 9-12; Volume 40, number 3, 4.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1995-1996. (Box 26)
    Volume 40, numbers 5- 12; Volume 41, numbers 1-7, 9.
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 1996-2001, 2003. (Box 27)
    Volume 41, number 11, 12; [Volume 42, number 1, 2, 4, 12]; [Volume 43, number 1]; [Volume 44, numbers 7,8]; [Volume 45, number 11]; [Volume 46, numbers 3, 9, 10]; [Volume 48, number 3, 8, 9].
  - LosAngeles Magazine (loose issues)., 2005-2006. (Box 28)
    [Volume 50, number 1, 2]; [Volume 51, number 5-8, 10, 12].
- Other Magazine Publications., 1950s-1990s.
  - Holiday (assorted issues)., late-1950s to mid-1960s. (Box 29)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. With 13 issue of the publication titled Holiday.
  - Loyalist (The) (assorted issues)., 1950-1954. (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Prompter (The) (assorted issues)., 1958-1959. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Westwind (3 issues)., 1957-1958. (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Assorted Magazine publications., 1950s. (Box 1, Folder 8)
    Down Beat (June 1954); Fortnight (Oct. 1956); L.A.:the Southern California Magazine (June 1959 and July- August 1960); The Record Changer (1951 Jul-Aug).
  - Assorted Magazine Publications., 1960s. (Box 30)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. 17 items
  - Assorted Magazine Publications., 1960s. (Box 31)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. 14 items
  - Assorted Magazine Publications., late 1970s to early 1990s. (Box 32)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. 23 items.
  - Assorted Magazine Publications., early 1950s to early 1970s. (Box 33)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. 22 items
  - Assorted Magazine Publication., early 1960s to mid 1980s. (Box 34)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. 16 items
  - Assorted Magazine Publications., 1990s. (Box 35)
    Magazines collected by Miller, containing stories pertaining to Los Angeles and/or Southern California. 5 items